<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Lovetoautomate.it - Sander de Groot - Nomadic Software Engineer</title>
    <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Lovetoautomate.it - Sander de Groot - Nomadic Software Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 20:41:40 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lovetoautomate.it/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What if recruiters would be software engineers themselves?</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2019/02/what-if-recruiters-would-be-software-engineers-themselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 20:41:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2019/02/what-if-recruiters-would-be-software-engineers-themselves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people in my profession will recognize the struggle. You&amp;rsquo;re receiving several messages a day from recruiters. On one hand, this makes you very happy because it means that there is a lot of work and, you are wanted! Though, there is another side to this story: the recruiters. Some would call it a love-hate relationship. But, what is actually happening here? And can we maybe change it for the better?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let &#34;Jack&#34; search for the cheapest flight tickets</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2019/01/let-jack-search-for-the-cheapest-flight-tickets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 20:42:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2019/01/let-jack-search-for-the-cheapest-flight-tickets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how some people seem to get ridicuously cheap tickets? The cheapest ticket from Amsterdam to Mexico you are able to find is about 600 euro return but your friend tells you he bought one for 350? How annoying. So, you just have to scour the internet a little more. OR, you just let Jack do the heavy lifting!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolut for Business: not living up to expectations</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2019/01/revolut-for-business-not-living-up-to-expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 20:35:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2019/01/revolut-for-business-not-living-up-to-expectations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Revolut, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the best banks for people who travel the world. With their free plan, you can pay in almost any currency without paying transaction fees or exchange surcharges. Their premium plan provides even more amazing features. When I&amp;rsquo;m abroad, my primary financial resource is this very service. So, when I started freelancing, I decided to give Revolut for Business a chance as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Nomad in Your Own Country</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2019/01/digital-nomad-in-your-own-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 21:08:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2019/01/digital-nomad-in-your-own-country/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More than a quarter has passed and so much has happened.
However, against all plans and expectations, I haven&amp;rsquo;t left the country yet.
Instead, I decided to start my digital nomad lifestyle in my own country, because well, why not?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on working remotely</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/09/my-thoughts-on-working-remotely/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 09:28:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/09/my-thoughts-on-working-remotely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working remotely. This is one of those subjects on which there is a thousand different opinions. And seeing I am planning to make a life as a digital nomad, I have thought quite a bit about this subject myself. In the past I have interviewed people and put together teams. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a strong advocate of having an on-site location. The past year I have realized and seen that it&amp;rsquo;s a mistake to assume it&amp;rsquo;s always the best way or that having remote working developers doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to start the next adventure</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/08/time-to-start-the-next-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 16:56:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/08/time-to-start-the-next-adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exciting! Finally I am ready to take the next step. I&amp;rsquo;ve sorted out the things I needed and started a business that allows me to begin my freelance work. The time has come to find my first assignment and with that, start my first adventure as digital nomad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An unexpected turn of events</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/07/an-unexpected-turn-of-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 08:28:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/07/an-unexpected-turn-of-events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I am almost 4,5 months into my journey and already flying back to the Netherlands. A lot has happened and I have made a couple of realizations that have made me (temporarily) come back sooner than planned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silence can be deafening</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/05/silence-can-be-deafening/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 20:51:32 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/05/silence-can-be-deafening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s 6 PM, it’s pitch dark outside and I’m all alone in my campervan. I have parked in a free camping spot near a swamp about 150km land inward. There’s nobody here except me and a some animals. I can’t see them but I know they’re there. I can tell, because, every once in a while some animal makes a screeching noise outside. However, most of the time, I hear nothing, nothing at all; complete silence. It’s somewhat disturbing really.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christchurch, on the other side of the world</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/03/christchurch-on-the-other-side-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 14:32:22 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/03/christchurch-on-the-other-side-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At last, I have arrived in the country I really wanted to go to: New Zealand. Without a plan or even the slightest idea on how to travel through New Zealand, I took the plane from the metropool Singapore to the country of backpackers!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singapore: the city of diversity</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/03/singapore-the-city-of-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 10:04:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/03/singapore-the-city-of-diversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On March 5, 2018, my journey finally started. The first stop you ask? Singapore! Spending a little over 6 days in this &lt;em&gt;city-state&lt;/em&gt;, allowed me to see quite a bit of what this city has to offer. My verdict? Must visit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to see more? Follow me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.polarsteps.com/luminosity/503421-backpacking-oceania-and-south-east-asia&#34;&gt;Polarsteps&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a really cool app, definitely worth taking a look if you are travelling yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trading a well-paid job for ultimate freedom</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/02/trading-a-well-paid-job-for-ultimate-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 08:28:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/02/trading-a-well-paid-job-for-ultimate-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you have to make a decision in your life that goes against everything you ever learned. Recently I made such a decision by quitting my job and buying a ticket to the other side of the world.
And now the adventure begins&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 10 things I learned from organizing my first meetup</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/01/the-10-things-i-learned-from-organizing-my-first-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 07:56:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/01/the-10-things-i-learned-from-organizing-my-first-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally it happened. On 30 januari 2018 I have organized &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Netherlands-Camunda-User-Group/events/245891545/&#34;&gt;my first meetup&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Netherlands-Camunda-User-Group/&#34;&gt;Netherlands Camunda User Group&lt;/a&gt;. What an experience was this. So much has happened to make this event come to life and using this blog post I want to share my experiences in the hopes to inspire others!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviving and repurposing this blog</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/01/reviving-and-repurposing-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2018/01/reviving-and-repurposing-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since my last post. I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to write an active blog but I somehow never find the time or the energy to start writing. It&amp;rsquo;s really a shame because writing usually really helps me with digesting my thoughts. Wether this is on a personal or on a professional level, writing helps me to think clearly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging without compromising on detail or performance</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2017/02/logging-without-compromising-on-detail-or-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2017/02/logging-without-compromising-on-detail-or-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Application logging. Have you ever had to choose between detailled logging or performance?
Where you on one side wanted to log something on a certain level of detail while
you knew that this would have an enormous impact on the performance of your application?
This is exactly the situation I was in while working on some high-load services at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twyp.com/&#34;&gt;Twyp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk: TWYP - An event driven architecture in a fast growing ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://lovetoautomate.it/2016/12/talk-twyp-an-event-driven-architecture-in-a-fast-growing-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lovetoautomate.it/2016/12/talk-twyp-an-event-driven-architecture-in-a-fast-growing-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>I was asked to give a talk on Event Driven Architectures at Landelijk Architectuur Congres. This Dutch conference was hosted in &amp;rsquo;s Hertogenbosch on November 17th-18th 2016.
The talk explains in more detail on how Twyp&amp;rsquo;s architecture is based on the reactive manifesto. During this presentation I am explaining how Twyp is architected and what we&amp;rsquo;ve learned in over two years of development.
Unfortunately the talk was not recorded. But you can find the slides on SlideShare.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>